(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.1",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 1,
"subtitles": 2
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
常闇トワ 4周年記念 LIVE
SPECIAL Thank U!! J Medley
Tokoyami Towa 4th Anniversary LIVE
bullet
作詞・作曲：中村未来
Lyrics & Composition: Miku Nakamura
くだらねぇ完璧なロジック
Meaningless, perfect logic
重すぎて首が落ちちゃう
It's so heavy my head might fall off
ねぇ見た目目の前のあの鍵は握ってるんでしょう
Hey, you're holding that key right in front of your eyes, aren't you?
飲み込まれないで　Hello
Don't get swallowed up, Hello
お前の欲しいものはなんなんだ
What is it that you want?
連れ出してよ　信じた道だけ
Take me away, only on the path I believed in
ゲームはいつでも勝者の手
The game is always in the winner's hands
無理矢理でも
Even if by force
貫いていくの
I'll keep pushing through
甘い囁きは幻覚論
Sweet whispers are just hallucinations
独り這い上がってた方がいい
It's better to crawl back up alone
傲慢な自由とやらは要らない
I don't need that so-called "arrogant freedom"
冗談でコントロールも効かない
Even as a joke, it can't be controlled
狭く狭い今を選択迫られ　嫌になるでしょう
Being forced to choose in this narrow, narrow present, you'll get sick of it, right?
たった一つだけ決めろ
Just decide on one thing
お前の譲れないものはなんなんだ
What is it that you won't give up?
認めてよ　歪な心
Acknowledge it, this warped heart
今だけは一歩も引けないんだ
Just for now, I can't take a single step back
目を覚まして
Open your eyes
bullet
…運命は止められない
...fate cannot be stopped.
「さよなら」は 引き止めてって
"Goodbye" means "please stop me from leaving."
「だいじょうぶ」は だいじょうぶじゃなくて
"I'm okay" means "I'm not okay."
「もういい」は 全然よくなくて
"It's fine" means "it's not fine at all."
そのままのワタシでいいって言って
Tell me that I'm fine just the way I am.
ノイズ
Noise
本当はもっともっと あなたの事を
Actually, I want to know more and more about you,
知りたいよって 一緒にいたいよって
that I want to know you, that I want to be with you.
伝えたら離れてしまいそうで
If I tell you, I'm afraid you'll leave.
だから守る事を幸せとした
So I made protecting this my happiness.
ねぇ ちゃんと目見て話したらきっと
Hey, if we speak while looking each other in the eye,
伝わる様な気がしてるんだよ
I feel like I'd surely be able to reach you.
面倒くさい 怖い 嫌い でも好き
Annoying, scary, hate, but still love.
おんなじなら
If it's the same...
キレイだと思った場所見つけて
Finding a place I thought was beautiful,
気に入ってただけだっただけだ
and just liking it was all it was.
逃げるヤツが幸せになる世界ならば
If this is a world where those who run away find happiness,
幸せなんて要らない 要らない
then I don't need happiness, I don't need it,
要らない もう要らない
I don't need it, I don't need it anymore.
いつだって一人で抱えるあなた
You, who are always shouldering things alone,
ただ見守るしか出来ない私
and me, who can only watch over you.
力になりたいと思うのに
Even though I want to be of help,
どうすればいいのか分からない
I don't know what I should do.
繰り返してく 忘れたらきっと
Repeating... if I forget, surely
誰かがまた傷付くから
someone else will get hurt again.
傷に傷を重ねたのは忘れる為？
Did I layer wound upon wound just to forget?
それとも…
Or is it...
「さよなら」は 引き止めてって
"Goodbye" means "please stop me from leaving."
「だいじょうぶ」は だいじょうぶじゃなくて
"I'm okay" means "I'm not okay."
「もういい」は 全然よくなくて
"It's fine" means "it's not fine at all."
そのままのワタシじゃダメなら
If I'm not good enough as I am...
ヘタクソな生き方でしか生きられない
We can only live in a clumsy way,
私達は
we...
一人では出来ない事も二人でなら
Even things we can't do alone, if we're together,
出来る様なそんな
we can do it, such a...
存在になりたかったな
I wanted to become such a presence.
言えない 言えない もう言えない
I can't say it, I can't say it, I can't say it anymore.
たったひとつ たったひとつの
The one and only, the one and only,
たったひとり たったひとりの
the one and only, the one and only,
私はここ
I am here.
Here
喘ぎの胸 息もできない
Panting chest, unable to breathe.
降り出す雨 眠るように
Falling rain, as if to sleep.
Cry...
この世界を生き抜くのならば
If I am to survive in this world,
どんな花を飾ればいいの
what kind of flowers should I decorate with?
信じたいくせに
Even though I want to believe,
信じられずに
I cannot believe.
無力で無意味な自分が
I, who am powerless and meaningless,
それでも心で泣いたんだ
Still cried in my heart
こっちへおいでと
Saying "Come over here"
声が聞こえる
I can hear a voice
無限で無謀な明日が
An infinite and reckless tomorrow
それでもどこかで待ってるから
Is still waiting somewhere, so...
たった一つ たった一つの
Only one, only one
たった一人 たった一人の
Only one person, only one person's
私はここ
I am here
半分しか許したくない
I only want to forgive half
半分しか分かり合えない
We can only understand each other halfway
この世界を戦い抜くなら
If I am to fight through this world,
どんな歌を歌えばいいの
What kind of song should I sing?
見つけたいなら
If you want to find it,
見つけ出すまで
Until I find it
不実で不毛な自由を
A faithless and fruitless freedom,
それでも欲しいと叫んだ
I still screamed that I wanted it
知ってるくせに
Even though you know,
知らんぷりをして
Pretending not to know,
無色で無傷な光を
A colorless and stainless light,
それでももう一度探した
I still searched for it once more
たった一つ たった一つの
Only one, only one,
たった一人 たった一人の
Only one person, only one person's,
私はここ
I am here
君だけの場所は
Your own place
必ずある
Will surely exist
美しいこの星は
This beautiful planet
すべてを隠してるけど
Is hiding everything, but...
無力で無意味な自分が
I, who am powerless and meaningless,
それでも心で泣いたんだ
Still cried in my heart
こっちへおいでと
Saying "Come over here"
声が聞こえる
I can hear a voice
無限で無謀な明日が
An infinite and reckless tomorrow
それでもどこかで待ってるから
Is still waiting somewhere, so...
たった一つ たった一つの
Only one, only one,
たった一人 たった一人の
Only one person, only one person's,
私はここ
I am here
SEVENTEEN
セブンティーン
Seventeen
鏡写しのような瓜二つの世界に
In two worlds like mirror images of each other
それぞれ生まれた二人の私
The two of me born in each
在るべき場所が違って 噛み様が間違った
The places we should be are different, God made a mistake
同じ姿形 中身は真反対
Same appearance, but the contents are polar opposites
一方はどうやら ずっと前に育てた
One seems to have been raised long ago
パパもママも大事に想ってる
By Mom and Dad, and cherishes them
だけど私はどうやら ここじゃ私じゃないから
But it seems I'm not me here
赤を青に 黒を白に戻すも
Whether I change red to blue, or black back to white
次元を隔てた向こう側の世界じゃ
In the world on the other side of the dimension
拒まれて残酷な夢が舞っている
I'm rejected, and cruel dreams are dancing
あっちの私も此処の私も泣き虫なの
The me over there and the me here are both crybabies
見て見ぬふりできない子が
The girl who can't pretend not to see...
此れじゃハッピーエンドとはいかない
This won't result in a happy ending
それじゃ絶望に行くね 世界
Then, I'm heading towards despair, world
こんな乱暴な私を許して
Forgive this violent me
きっと遣り遂げるから
I'll surely get it done
これはバッドエンドなんかじゃない
This isn't some kind of bad ending
どこにいたとしても私は
Wherever I may be, I will always
そう世界で独りのオリジナル
remain the one and only original in this world.
誇らしく思って
I'll think of it with pride...
増えてな 嬉しいな
...and I'd be happy if there were more.
境界の線で切り分けて
Cutting through the boundary line,
こちら側の世界で
in the world on this side,
冗談な君の天使が
your joke of an angel
首を振る
shakes its head.
気づいてしまった
I've realized it now,
悪は見逃せばいいから
so just look the other way from evil.
帰り道を交換しよう
Let's swap our ways home.
私が希望になるの
I will become the hope.
お別れは少し寂しいけれど
Saying goodbye is a little lonely, but...
いつか目尻に作った傷も
even the scar I once made by my eye...
誇りに立ち向かった証だから
...is proof that I stood tall with pride.
いつかハッピーエンドになるまで
Until a happy ending comes one day,
世界を相手に戦うの
I'll keep fighting against the world.
こんな乱暴な私をずっと
For always loving
愛してくれてありがとう
such a rowdy person like me, thank you.
これはバッドエンドなんかじゃない
This is by no means a bad ending.
どこにいたとしても私は
Wherever I may be, I will always
あなたの唯一無二のオリジナル
remain your one and only original.
誇らしく生きるよ
I'll live with pride.
さぁあるべき場所に帰ろう
Now, let's return to where we belong.
さよなら 追憶のセブンティーン
Farewell, the Seventeen of my memories.
オートマチック！
Automatic!
街を 切り裂くような排気音が
An exhaust note that seems to tear through the city
足元で唸っている
is roaring beneath my feet.
猛スピードで進む
Moving at breakneck speed,
消えた テールランプの在り処
searching for where the taillights vanished,
探して真っ直ぐに
I head straight forward.
闇を スクラップにする強さで
With a strength that turns darkness into scrap,
ひた走る道路にはもう
there are no longer any streetlights
街灯さえないけれど
on the road I'm speeding along, but...
きっと ヘッドライト一つあれば
surely, as long as I have a single headlight,
何もいらないな
I don't need anything else.
ガレキの下に埋もれた 弱虫の声は
The voice of a coward buried under the rubble...
いくら耳澄ましても 聞こえやしないさ
...cannot be heard, no matter how hard I listen.
追いかけてくる後悔が 視界を塞ぐ前に
Before the chasing regrets can block my view,
追いついた未来の端っこで何度も
at the edge of the future I've caught up to,
あなたを救い出すよ
I will save you over and over again.
不意に 記憶がブレーキをかけた
Suddenly, my memories slammed on the brakes.
舌打ちの矛先は
The target of my clicking tongue
覗き込むミラーの向こう
is beyond the mirror I'm peering into.
自分の 意気地なさに気づいている
I've realized my own lack of courage,
時間などないのに
even though there's no time to waste.
ガレキの下から漏れた 弱虫の声は
The voice of a coward leaking from under the rubble...
いくら耳塞いでも 痛いほど響いてた
...echoed painfully, no matter how I covered my ears.
あの日交わした返事を 忘れてたまるもんかと
Vowing never to forget the answer we swapped that day,
震えた心が今も うるさいほど
my trembling heart, even now,
その名前を叫んでる
is screaming that name so loud it's noisy.
ヒーロー ぶって笑っていた
Until I can wipe
あなたの両頬を
both of your cheeks
拭うまで止まらない
that were smiling while acting like a hero, I won't stop.
あぁそうさ あの夜から
Ah, that's right. Since that night,
あなたを迎えに来たんだ
I've come to get you.
何度しくじろうとも
No matter how many times I might fail.
ホワイトノイズ
White Noise
ヒーローぶって笑っていた
Pretending to be a hero and laughing
あなたの絶望を
Your despair
抱きしめるまで 負けない
I won't give up until I embrace it
運命に殴られても
Even if fate punches me
痛くも痒くもない
It doesn't hurt or itch at all
ドロドロを駆け抜けていく
Running through the mud
瓦礫の下に埋もれた声を
The voices buried under the rubble
かき消しながら
While drowning them out
I'm a mess, I'm a mess
明けない夜に
In the night that never ends
失いかけた声をあげて
I raise the voice I almost lost
I'm a mess, I'm a mess
振り返れない
I can't look back
僕の心はどこへ行くの
Where is my heart going?
I'm a mess
作詞：Hiro 作曲：Hiro 編曲：SHO
Lyrics: Hiro / Composition: Hiro / Arrangement: SHO
閉ざされたような世の中で
In a world that feels closed off
何が不要不急かも わからなくなってしまう
I can't even tell what's essential and what's not
信じられているメッセージ
The messages that are believed
隠された口元じゃ何も言えないだろう
You can't say anything with a covered mouth, can you?
満たされない日々に
In these unfulfilled days
笑われたくもないな
I don't want to be laughed at
心の底から
From the bottom of my heart
崩れかけた
It's starting to crumble
I'm a mess, I'm a mess
独りの夜は こんな想いが溢れていく
Alone at night, these feelings overflow
I'm a mess, I'm a mess
余裕のないネガティブ 同じように苦しめられて
Burdened by negativity, suffering just like everyone else
要らない要らない宣言なんて 何度繰り返せばいいの
How many times must we repeat these "don't need it" declarations?
もう意味なんてないよな
They don't mean anything anymore
I'm a mess, I'm a mess
独りの夜も 乗り越えられればいいのにな
I wish I could overcome these lonely nights
真っ暗な街中を 憂い帯びた顔で
Through the pitch-black city streets, with a face full of sorrow
バラバラに立ち去っていく
Everyone goes their separate ways
簡単に作られた 意図的なマニュアルに
By a manual designed to be simple and intentional
全て奪われている
Everything is being taken away
今の世界は先が見えずに
In today's world, we can't see the future
どこにも救いはなくて
There's no salvation anywhere
また次の犠牲者が
And yet another victim
増えていくの
Is added to the count
I'm a mess, I'm a mess
聞こえぬ声を 探し続けてたどり着いた
I kept searching for unheard voices and finally arrived
I'm a mess, I'm a mess
不安な毎日 もっと近くで触れたいのに
In these anxious days, I want to be closer to you
眠れないシンデレラ
The Cinderella who can't sleep
まだ帰る時間じゃないのに
It's not time to go home yet
魔法が解けていくの
But the magic is fading away
I'm a mess, I'm a mess
いつかはきっと 朝まで踊り明かしたいな
Someday, I'm sure, I'll want to dance until morning
当たり前じゃないだろ
It's not natural, is it?
辞めたわけじゃないよな
You haven't quit, have you?
だとしたら答え探して
If so, then search for the answer
I'm a mess, I'm a mess, I'm a mess
あの日の僕は 夢は叶うと思ったけど
That day, I thought dreams would come true
I'm a mess, I'm a mess
諦めたくないなんて言葉じゃ 頼りなくて
The words "I don't want to give up" are so unreliable
I'm a mess, I'm a mess
独りの夜は
On lonely nights
こんな想いが溢れていく
These feelings overflow
I'm a mess, I'm a mess
余裕のないネガティブ 同じように苦しめられて
Burdened by negativity, suffering just like everyone else
要らない要らない宣言なんて
These "don't need it" declarations
何度繰り返せばいいの
How many times must we repeat them?
もう意味なんてないよな
They don't mean anything anymore
I'm a mess, I'm a mess
どんな世界も 君と歩いて行けるのなら
If I can walk with you through any kind of world
ほら定めた位置から変えたの
See, I changed it from the set position.
君しかいないとか言ってよ
Say something like there's no one but you.
フラつきたいから愛したの
I loved because I wanted to waver.
ダリラリラッタッタラ
Dari-ra-ri-rat-tat-ta-ra
ハレンチ
作詞：ちゃんみな 作曲：ちゃんみな/BENA
Harenchi
Lyrics: CHANMINA Composition: CHANMINA/BENA
鳴り覚えがあるから
Since I remember the sound,
鼻をかいたの
I scratched my nose.
大人びてしまった私は
I, who have grown up,
近頃遊んでいたの
have been playing around lately.
日和も地もグラ度も
The weather, the ground, the gradation too...
任せてみても
Even if I leave it to you,
なんでもなんでも
it's nothing, nothing,
なんでもなんでもないのね
nothing at all.
さあ私 さあ私 さあ私
Now me, now me, now me,
この浮き心地に
in this floating feeling,
誰が気づくというの
who would notice?
どうでもいいから泣いたの
I cried because I didn't care.
乱れ心も抱いてよ
Embrace my disturbed heart too.
代わりに何かよこしてよ
Give me something in return.
ダリラリラッタッタラ
Dari-ra-ri-rat-tat-ta-ra
Yeah yeah yeah 忘れた
Yeah yeah yeah, I forgot.
何の感覚もない Yeah yeah
There's no sensation at all, yeah yeah.
Yeah yeah yeah 忘れた
Yeah yeah yeah, I forgot.
あなたを知りたかったから
Because I wanted to know you.
Go and take me out 行ってよ東京さん
Go and take me out, tell me Mr. Tokyo.
都会は大嫌い
I hate the city.
埃っぽくて冷たい
Dusty and cold.
忙しくて愛らしい Yeah
Busy and lovely, yeah.
化粧気のない私は
I, without any makeup,
はい 誰が愛でるのに誰もいないわ
yes, although who would admire me, there's no one.
どこに どこに どこに
Where, where, where...
誰もいなくなれ
May everyone disappear.
感謝も愛も細切れにして
Cut up gratitude and love into pieces.
なんの なんの なんの
What... what... what...
気にしてるの
are you worried about?
悪ふざけしないでいいから
Because you don't need to fool around.
なぜか強い夜が明けて
Somehow, a strong night dawns.
君の匂いが消えて
Your scent disappears.
一人になったらどうしよう
What should I do if I'm alone?
ダリラリラッタッタラ
Dari-ra-ri-rat-tat-ta-ra
ほら定めた位置から泣いたの
See, I cried from the set position.
君しかいないから変えたの
I changed it because there's only you.
愛されたいから愛したの
I loved because I wanted to be loved.
ダリラリラッタッタラ
Dari-ra-ri-rat-tat-ta-ra
Yeah yeah yeah 忘れた
Yeah yeah yeah, I forgot.
何の感覚もない Yeah yeah
There's no sensation at all, yeah yeah.
Yeah yeah yeah 忘れた
Yeah yeah yeah, I forgot.
あなたを知りたかったから
Because I wanted to know you.
月を見ていた
作詞・作曲：米津玄師
Tsuki wo Miteita
Lyrics & Composition: Kenshi Yonezu
月明かり柳が揺れる
Moonlight, the willow sways.
私は路傍のつぶて
I am a stone by the roadside.
思い馳せるあなたの姿
Thinking of your image.
羊を数えるように
Like counting sheep.
別れゆく意味があるなら
If there is a meaning to parting,
全て悲しまないで
don't be sad about everything.
しじまから離れた空へ
To the sky away from the silence.
一筋の愛を込めて
With a single streak of love.
どんな夜だって
No matter what kind of night it is,
失い続けたって
even if I keep losing,
共に生きていこう
let's live together.
瞬くように
Like a twinkle.
何かを求めて月を見ていた
I was looking at the moon, seeking something.
嵐に怯える私の前に
In front of me, who is afraid of the storm.
月を見ていた
Moonwatching
あらわれたのがあなたでよかった
I'm glad it was you who appeared
まるでなにもかもがなかったかのように
As if everything was for naught
この日は消えたりしない　きっと
This day will surely not fade away
その窓を風が叩けば
If the wind knocks on that window
わずかに笑顔放して
Let out a slight smile
ただ一つ　そうただ一つ
Only one, yes, only one
語りえぬ声で叫ぶ
Screaming in an unspeakable voice
生まれ変わったとしても
Even if I were to be reborn
思い出せなくたって見つけてみせるだろう
I'd find you even if I couldn't remember
あなたの姿
Your figure
全てを燃やして月を見ていた
I was watching the moon while burning everything
誰かがそれをあわれむとしても
Even if someone pities that
あなたがいれば幸せだったんだ
I was happy as long as you were there
およそ正しさなどなかったとしても
Even if there was almost no correctness
消えてしまわない　きっと
It surely won't disappear
名前を呼んでもう一度だけ
Call my name just one more time
優しく包むその弱い声で
With that weak voice that gently envelops
月を頼りに掴んだ笑顔があなただった
The smile I grasped by the moonlight was you
あなただった
It was you
何かを求めて月を見ていた
I was watching the moon, seeking something
嵐に怯える私の前に
In front of me, trembling in the storm
あらわれたのがあなたでよかった
I'm glad it was you who appeared
まるでなにもかもがなかったかのように
As if everything was for naught
この日は消えたりしない　きっと
This day will surely not fade away
ダーリン 作詞・作曲: 須田景凪
Darling / Lyricist & Composer: Suda Keina
ダーリン
Darling
私じゃ駄目ですか？
Am I not good enough?
誰よりあなたを
More than anyone else, I...
わかってるの　わかってるのはきっと私だけ
I know... I'm surely the only one who knows you
私じゃ駄目ですか？
Am I not good enough?
心は奪えない
I can't steal your heart
わかってるの　わかってるのはきっと私だけ
I know... I'm surely the only one who knows you
ダーリン全部あなたにあげる
Darling, I'll give you everything
お気持ちはちゃんと愛で頂戴
Please accept my feelings with love
ダーリンいつか認めておくれ
Darling, acknowledge me someday
その日が来るのを待っているわ　ダーリン
I'm waiting for that day to come, Darling
一人じゃ意味がない
It's meaningless alone
言葉は生まれない
Words aren't born
わかってるの　わかってるのにずっと逸らさずに
I know... I know, yet I keep my eyes on you
二人じゃいられない
We can't be together
心は触れない
I can't touch your heart
わかってるの　わかってるのにずっと恥じらわず
I know... I know, yet I'm never ashamed
私じゃ駄目ですか
Am I not good enough?
ダーリン全部あなたにあげる
Darling, I'll give you everything
お遊び夢中でなんて狼狽
What a mess, being so absorbed in play
ダーリン いつか
Darling, someday
忘れておくれ
please forget me.
終わりがくるのを 待っているわ
I'm waiting for the end to come.
ダーリン 全部 あなたにあげる
Darling, I'll give you everything.
お気持ちはちゃんと 空けてちょうだい
Please make sure your heart is empty.
ダーリン いつか 認めておくれ
Darling, someday please acknowledge me.
その日がくるのを 待っているわ
I'm waiting for that day to come.
ダーリン
Darling
行くぞー！
Here we go!
ラストチャンスに飢えたつま先が
Toes hungry for a last chance
踊り出すまま 駆けたこの夜空
ran through this night sky while dancing.
並みのスタンスじゃ靡かない
Won't flutter with an average stance,
星は宝石の憧れ
stars are jewels of longing.
浮かぶ涙と汗は血の代わり
Floating tears and sweat instead of blood.
瞳の中でしか泳げない芝居
A play that can only swim in the eyes,
だけどステージが逃がさない
but the stage won't let go.
いついつまでも憧れ
Longing forever and ever,
焦がれているよ
I'm pining for it.
I've never seen such a liar
生まれついたっての嘘つき
Born to be such a liar.
This is love. And this is a gift to the world.
誰を生きたか思い出して
Remembering who I lived as,
私が命を賭けるから
because I'm betting my life.
あげるから
I'll give it to you.
あなたは時間をくれたのでしょう
You probably gave me time,
あらゆる望みの総てを
all of every desire.
叶えたら 果たせたら
If they come true, if they're fulfilled,
あなたに会いたい 星に願いをかけて
I want to see you, making a wish on a star.
戻れないから大切にするの
Cherishing it because I can't go back.
始めないなら高を括れるよ
I can underestimate it if I don't start.
報いの日（楽になる日）はまず来ない
The day of reckoning won't come soon.
日々の中に集まる
Gathering in the days,
悲しい光
a sad light.
生まれついたっての嘘つき
Born to be such a liar.
This is love. And this is a gift to the world.
誰を生きたか
Who did I live as?
忘れちゃった！
I forgot!
あなたに命が戻るなら
If life returns to you,
届くなら
if it reaches you.
私はどうなろうと構わないのに
Even though I don't care what happens to me.
どうやら総ては叶わない
It seems all will not come true.
叶わないならば
If they don't come true,
あなたになりたい 星は砕け光る
I want to become you; stars shatter and shine.
私が命を賭けるから
Because I'm betting my life,
あげるから
I'll give it to you.
あなたは時間をくれたのでしょう
You gave me time, didn't you?
あらゆる望みの総てを
All of every desire.
叶えたら 果たせたら
If they come true, if they're fulfilled,
あなたに会いたい 星に願いをかけて
I want to see you, making a wish on a star.
さあ星の子たちよ よくお眠りなさい
Now, children of the stars, sleep well.
輝きは鈍らない あなたたちならば
The radiance will not fade, if it's you.
さあ星の子たちよ よく狙いなさい
Now, children of the stars, aim well.
瞬きを許さない あなたたちならば
I won't allow a blink, if it's you.
歌ってきましたが、いかがだったでしょうか？
I've been singing, how was it?
イェーイ！ノンストップメドレー！
Yay! Non-stop medley!
生誕祭とかね、周年記念はね
For birthday celebrations and anniversary commemorations...
今までね結構ホロライブメンバーの楽曲を歌わせてもらったりとか
I've been singing a lot of songs by Hololive members until now...
ホロライブが作ってるオリジナルね
Or original songs made by Hololive.
...ていただいたので
...since I was given the opportunity,
こうやってJ-POPの楽曲をたくさん歌うのは初めてなんじゃないかなと思います。
I think this is the first time I've sung so many J-Pop songs like this.
はい。そしてね、いっぱいね、曲をね、聴いてもらいたかったので、MCもちょっと少なめにしてみました。ういー！
Yes. And, I wanted you all to hear many songs, so I kept the MC section short. Whew!
あ、よかった？
Oh, was it good?
ありがとう。ありがとう、ありがとう、ありがとう、ありがとう。ありがとう。
Thank you. Thank you, thank you, thank you, thank you. Thank you.
やっぱマイク持つとねテンション上がるね。ありがとう、ありがとう。
Holding a mic really gets me pumped up. Thank you, thank you.
そしてね、曲なんですけれども、なんかね、あの、流行りの曲とかを、こう調べて、ちょっと歌ってみたりとか、あとは自分がね、歌いたい曲をね、入れ込んでみました！
And about the songs, I researched popular ones to sing, and I also included songs that I personally wanted to sing!
何曲かはね、ちょっとね、カバー動画にしたいなと思っております。はい。
I'm thinking of making cover videos for some of these songs. Yes.
そしてね、なんと、え、残り2曲！最後までね、盛り上がっていただければなと思います。
And now, believe it or not, there are only 2 songs left! I hope you'll all keep the energy up until the end.
はい。では、それでは聞いてください。YOASOBIさんの「アドベンチャー」。
Alright. Now, please listen. 'Adventure' by YOASOBI.
いつもの一日から抜け出して
Escape from the usual day-to-day
目が覚めるような冒険の舞台へ
To a stage of eye-opening adventure
回る地球儀を目印に
Using the spinning globe as our guide
さあ今会いに行こう 特別な一日に
Come, let's go meet this special day now
芽吹く新しい季節に
In the budding new season
一人見つめたブルースカイ
I gazed at the blue sky alone
顔も知らない友達に 満たないクラスメイト
Classmates who aren't even friends whose faces I don't know
想定外の暮らし
An unexpected way of life
こんなんじゃない 模索した理想と真反対に
It wasn't supposed to be like this, the polar opposite of the ideal I sought
淡々と過ぎる毎日
Every day passes by indifferently
でもやっと会えるね 想像と現実が交じって
But finally, we can meet, where imagination and reality merge
高鳴る胸 抑えられない
I can't suppress my pounding heart
約束の場所は
The promised place
夢見ていた場所
Is the place I dreamed of
忘れられない一日が今始まる
An unforgettable day begins now
待ちに待った今日は特別な日
Today is the long-awaited special day
日常から少しはみ出して
Stepping out of the everyday a little
ほらシャッターを切って映し出せば
Look, if you press the shutter and capture it
どうしたって溢れるような笑顔ばかり
No matter what, it's just overflowing with smiles
次はどこに行こうか
Where shall we go next?
軽やかに歩く
Walking with a light step
不思議なほどに気が付けば過ぎている時間
Time passes by so strangely fast when I notice it
太陽が沈んだ街を飾る
Decorating the town where the sun has set
光が織りなすパレードに
In the parade woven with light
心奪われ噛み締める
I'm captivated and savor the moment
ああ本当にここに来れて良かったな
Ah, I'm really glad I could come here
待ちに待った今日は特別な日
Today is the long-awaited special day
いつも通りから飛び出して
Breaking out from the usual routine
ほらシャッターを切っても写せない
Look, even if you press the shutter, you can't capture
思い出がいつでも待っている
The memories that are always waiting
春も夏も秋も冬も
In spring, summer, autumn, and winter
この場所で見つけたい笑顔が
The smiles I want to find in this place
ひらひらといくつも積もっていく
Accumulate one after another, fluttering down
さあ次はいつ会いに来れるかな
Come, I wonder when I can come to see you next?
当たり前を抜け出して 限界の無い冒険の舞台へ
Escaping from the ordinary, to a stage of limitless adventure
回る地球儀を目印に
Using the spinning globe as our guide
さあ今会いに行こう 特別な一日に
Come, let's go meet this special day now
はい、アドベンチャーでした！ありがとうございました！
Yes, that was 'Adventure'! Thank you so much!
可愛かったでしょ、振り付け。こういう振り付け。
The choreography was cute, wasn't it? A choreography like this.
チャン、チャン、ハイ。
Step, step, yes.
これピースなのも。
This part is a peace sign too.
はい、まそんなことはどうでもいいとして。
Well, anyway, putting that aside.
J-POPメドレーはこちらで終わりたいと思います。
I'll end the J-pop medley here.
はい、そしてここからは、えー、おなじみ告知メ...
Alright, and from here, the usual announcement med...
告知メドレーだ。告知メドレー！
It's an announcement medley. An announcement medley!
はい、おなじみのグッズの告知です！
Alright, it's time for the usual merch announcement!
デレレレレン、ボーン！
Drumroll... Boom!
常闇トワ 4周年記念グッズ 発売決定！
Tokoyami Towa 4th Anniversary Merch Release Confirmed!
グッズの種類が3種類となっております。
There are three types of merchandise.
はい、B2タペストリー、眷属ロングTシャツ、ビビぬいぐるみキーホルダー、そして特典にポストカードがついてきます。
B2 tapestry, Kenzoku long T-shirt, Bibi plushie keyholder, and a bonus postcard.
こちらの特典ですね、数量限定で直筆サイン入りポストカードがついてきます。
This bonus comes with a limited quantity of autographed postcards.
直筆のサインはね、本当に久しぶりに書くので、ぜひね、ゲットしていただきたいなと思います。
It's been a long time since I've signed anything, so I hope you'll get one.
はい、では各グッズのご紹介！
Alright, let's introduce each item!
まず1つ目はB2タペストリーです。
The first item is a B2 tapestry.
イラスト秋赤音さんに描いていただきました。
The illustration was done by Aki Akane.
昔からね本当に大好きなイラストレーター様で、
She's an illustrator I've really loved for a long time.
お歌も上手いし、もうずっと尊敬する人にね、描いていただいたので
She's also a great singer, and having someone I've always respected draw this...
もう本当に嬉しかったので、みんなもね、ぜひ手に入れてください。
...made me so happy, so please be sure to get one.
そして2つ目は眷属ロングTシャツ。
The second item is the Kenzoku long T-shirt.
えー、前にね、結構昔かな。
Um, quite a while ago...
あの、ロングTシャツを黒色で出したので、今回は白にしてみました。
...I released a black long T-shirt, so I went with white this time.
その時にもね、好評だったので。
It was well-received back then, too.
しかもトワもね、「うわ、めっちゃ使いやすいじゃん」と思って購入して
And since I also thought, "Wow, this is so easy to use," and bought it...
もう一回ね、いいなと思ったので今回作ることにしました。
...I decided to make it again because I really liked it.
腕の部分にはトワの名前が入っておりまして、
My name is printed on the sleeve,
なんと胸のところにはイラストも入っております。
and there's an illustration on the chest as well!
いや、カラーじゃなくてね、モノトーンっぽい感じにしたんですけど、
I decided to go with a monotone look instead of color.
ま、このね、理由としては、普段の服にも使えそうかなって思ってこのようなデザインにしました。
The reason for that is I wanted a design that could be worn as everyday clothes.
え、実際にトワも、こういう服を使ってるんですけど、
Actually, I wear clothes like this myself.
ま、そのジャージっぽくない感じ？
Like, it doesn't look like a sports jersey?
このカラーを止めることによってすごいジャージっぽくなくて
By avoiding colors, it doesn't feel like a jersey at all,
普段使いしやすいような感じだったので、
and it felt perfect for everyday use.
本当になんか自分も結構使ってるから、欲しいなと思って作ったっていうのもあります。
I use them quite a bit, so I made this because I wanted one myself.
そして、グッズ最後！ビビぬいぐるみキーホルダー。
And for the final item! The Bibi plushie keyholder.
え、以前ね、ビビのぬいぐるみを出したときに、
When I released the Bibi plushie before,
ホロメンからもね、「大好評、可愛い！」って言ってもらったりとか、
it was super popular with other Hololive members, who said it was cute...
「ぬいぐるみ欲しい！」って言ってお渡しした子もいて。
...and some even asked for one, so I gave them some.
で、自分の中でもね、「え、めっちゃ可愛いじゃん」と思っていたので、
I thought it was really cute myself,
そのね、あの、でっかい、抱っこできるぐらいの大きさだったビビを
so I took that big, huggable-sized Bibi...
ギュッと小さくしてキーホルダーにしてもらいました。
...and had it shrunk down into a keyholder.
え、めっちゃ可愛いのでね、ぜひ購入してみてください。
It's really cute, so please check it out.
ということで、グッズの紹介でした。
So, that was the merch introduction.
え、各グッズセットもあるし、単品販売もあるので、
There are sets as well as individual items for sale.
ぜひ、この後概要欄をチェックしてみてください。よろしくお願いします。
So please check the description box after the stream. Thank you!
というわけで、グッズ告知でした！
And that's it for the merch announcement!
はい、はい、概要欄にね、URLを載せておきますので、配信後にご購入をお願いいたします。
I'll put the URL in the description, so please buy them after the stream.
はい、そして初めて、なんとこの後、メンバーシップ限定のライブをやりたいと思います！
And for the first time, I'll be doing a membership-only live stream after this!
打ち上げみたいな感じだね。
It'll be like an after-party.
え、メンバーシップのね、そのライブでは盛り上がる曲を歌おうかなと思っておりますので、
I'm planning to sing some high-energy songs during that stream,
ぜひメンバーシップ登録をよろしくお願いします。
so please consider joining my membership.
マジでさ、みんながやっててさ、「あ、いいな」と思いつつもやってこなかったメンバーシップ限定ライブ。
I've seen others doing membership-only lives and thought it looked nice, but I've never done one.
今回初めてやりますのでよろしくお願いします。
I'll be doing it for the first time, so thank you!
はい、そして最後。告知あります、まだあります。これが最後。
Alright, and finally. One more announcement! This is the last one.
「な、なんだってー！うわー！」というコメントがいっぱい流れています。
I'm seeing a lot of "What?! No way!" comments.
自演（笑）。
I'm just making that up myself (laughs).
はい。いや、これちょっと分かってるかな。
Alright. I wonder if you can guess what it is.
あ、いや、分かってないよね。うん、分かってないよね。
Ah, no, you don't know yet. Yeah, you don't know.
はい、そうです。なんとびっくりしたでしょ。新曲あります！イエーイ！
That's right! You'll be surprised. I have a new song! Yay!
え、「雷鳴」も手がけてくださった和楽器さんに、また書き下ろししていただきました。
I had Wazzy, who also worked on "Raimei," write another song for me.
はい。爽やかなね、爽やかなねとか言って。
Yeah. It's a refreshing... "refreshing"...
どうなってんだ。「爽やかなね、爽やかなロック調の」
What's going on? "A refreshing... refreshing rock-style"...
どんだけ噛むんだ。
How many times am I going to stutter?
爽やかなロック調の楽曲になっております。
It's a refreshing rock-style song.
え、タイトルは「S.T.Y.」というタイトルになっております。
The title is "S.T.Y."
え、ジャケットはこんな感じ。テヤン！
Here's what the cover looks like. Ta-da!
こちらもね、なんとグッズとして、あのCDとしてシングルとして発売されるので
This will also be released as a CD single as part of the merch set.
是非チェックをよろしくお願いします。
Please be sure to check it out.
はい、S.T.Y.っていうのはね、何かの略なんです。
Yes, "S.T.Y." is an abbreviation for something.
えー、こちらのね、何の略かといういうのは歌詞の中に...
As for what it's an abbreviation for, in the lyrics...
...答えが載ってるかもしれない。
...the answer might be in there.
というか、すでに答えが載ってるかもしれない。
Actually, the answer might already be out there.
まあそんなことはいいんだけど、考えながら聴いてくれれば嬉しいです。
Well, anyway, I'd be happy if you listened while thinking about it.
それでは聴いてください、S.T.Y.。
Now, please listen: "S.T.Y."
そっと振り返った奇跡　どうしたって光って
The miracle I quietly looked back on, no matter what, it shines
ありふれた君がいつだってスーパーヒーロー
The ordinary you is always a superhero
ハ！ハ！ハ！ハ！
Ha! Ha! Ha! Ha!
いつもポンコツだった私　飛べなくて未完成
I was always a klutz, unable to fly and incomplete
アヒルなのはアヒルのままかもねなんてさ
Thinking that maybe a duck will just stay a duck
らしさなんて放っておいて　君となんかちょっと似ていて
Forget about "being myself", I'm somewhat like you
デコボコだからジャストに噛み合うパズルピース
Because we're uneven, we fit perfectly like puzzle pieces
繋げたい　繋ぎたい　届かない言葉も
I want to connect, I want to join, even words that don't reach
いつかは誰かの何かに成りたいから
Because someday I want to become something to someone
crazy No lazy 夢の中
crazy No lazy, in the middle of a dream
夢を見せて
Show me a dream
Always going 何千回　何万回　膝をついても
Always going, thousands, tens of thousands of times, even if I fall to my knees
最大級 I love you で立ち上がれるから
Because I can stand up with a maximum-level "I love you"
とびっきりオーバーな S.T.Y.
A super extraordinary S.T.Y.
消えそうなハッピーも勇気も振り絞っちゃって
Squeezing out every bit of fading happiness and courage
大失敗も後悔さえ愛せるなら
If I can even love big failures and regrets
背中には君という羽
Then on my back, I have wings called "you"
ハ！ハ！ハ！ハ！
Ha! Ha! Ha! Ha!
チクタク追い越して　いつもどこか乾いた焦燥感
Overtaking the tick-tock, always a dry sense of impatience somewhere
隣で走る君と織り成すブレイブストーリー
A brave story woven together with you running beside me
Non-fiction
君の色が私を塗り替えて
Your color repaints me
壊れかけの音で響くから
Because it resonates with a nearly broken sound
おとぎ話の続きをまだ描きたいんだよ
I still want to draw the continuation of the fairy tale
Palette Palette 連れて行くよ
Palette Palette, I'll take you with me
きっと何千回　何万回...
Surely thousands, tens of thousands of times...
きっと何千回　何万回
Surely thousands, tens of thousands of times
Always going 何千回　何万回　迷い込んでも
Always going, thousands, tens of thousands of times, even if I get lost
最大級 I love you な君がいるから
Because there's a maximum-level "I love you" version of you
弾丸ノバシャルな S.T.Y.
A bullet-like special S.T.Y.
それでもってラッキーも運命も手繰り寄せて
And then, pulling in both luck and destiny
もうバイバイも涙も怖くないよ
I'm no longer afraid of goodbyes or tears
飛べなかった私のこの背中には君という羽
On this back of mine that couldn't fly, I have wings called "you"
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!
ありがとうございましたー！
Thank you very much!
5周年目もよろしくねー！
Please support me in my 5th year too!
またねー！
See you later!
常闇トワ4周年記念ライブ、スペシャルサンキュージェーメドレー、いかがだったでしょうか？
How was the Tokoyami Towa 4th Anniversary Live: Special Thank U J-Medley?
ライブタイトルは先ほど披露いたしました、buzzGさん作詞作曲の「S.T.Y.」とかけて決めました。
The live title was chosen as a play on "S.T.Y.", written and composed by buzzG, which I just performed.
いつもみんなありがとう！
Thank you everyone, as always!
こちらの「S.T.Y.」と合わせて、ホロライブオリジナル曲「至上主義アドトラック」常闇トワカバーバージョンが、CDシングルとして発売いたします！
Together with "S.T.Y.", the Hololive original song "Shijou Shugi Adtruck" Tokoyami Towa cover version will be released as a CD single!
概要欄を更新してみて確認してみてください。
Please check the description box for updates.
常闇トワ 1st Single S.T.Y. (SPECIAL THANK YOU!!)
Tokoyami Towa 1st Single S.T.Y. (SPECIAL THANK YOU!!)
収録楽曲
01: S.T.Y.
02: S.T.Y. (Instrumental)
03: 至上主義アドトラック (常闇トワカバー ver.)
Tracklist
01: S.T.Y.
02: S.T.Y. (Instrumental)
03: Shijou Shugi Adtrack (Tokoyami Towa Cover ver.)
例えば、今夜2024年1月4日0時にも配信されます。
For example, it will also be released at midnight tonight, January 4th, 2024.
CDシングルが届く前にぜひ聴いてみてください。
Please be sure to listen to it before your CD single arrives.
至上主義アドトラックはCDシングル購入者のみにしか聴けないので、
"Shijou Shugi Adtrack" is only available to those who purchase the CD single,
そちらも聴きたい方はぜひCDをご購入ください！
so if you'd like to hear it, please consider buying the CD!
では、感想は #常闇トワ4周年記念ライブ でたくさん呟いてね！
Please tweet your impressions using the hashtag #TokoyamiTowa4thAnniversaryLive!
今日は本当にありがとう！常闇トワでした！
Thank you so much for today! This was Tokoyami Towa!